Guide to the Stayton Nunn papers, 1927-1967 MS 389
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Stayton Nunn papers
1927-1967
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Nunn, Addison Stayton
MS 389
1 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection contains Stayton Nunn's papers from 1927-1967 and includes notes and materials related to architecture classes, building projects in the Houston area, house plans and other architectural-related papers. Nunn taught architecture classes at the Rice Institute and was an alumnus as well.
Biographical / Historical
Addison Stayton Nunn graduated from the Rice Institute in 1921, won several national architecture competitions, and was credited with creating "Houston architecture," a type of home adapted to the Houston climate. He became an Assistant Professor of Architecture in 1928 and became a Fellow in Architecture in 1930. In 1934, he was promoted to Instructor of Architectural Construction and taught until 1945. Nunn also worked for William Ward Watkin at his architectural firm and helped Watkin design some of his best buildings.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Stayton Nunn's papers from 1927-1967 and includes notes and materials related to architecture classes, building projects in the Houston area, house plans and other architectural-related papers. The collection also contains a Harvard University Graduate School of Architecture course catalog, Royal Institute of British Architects publications, Rice Architecture alumni correspondence, and a proposed building program for Galveston Public Schools. Nunn taught architecture classes at the Rice Institute and was an alumnus as well.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated to Fondren by Stayton Nunn ('21) and was received in April 1987.
Index Terms
Subjects
Architecture
Document Types
notes; lecture notes; letters (correspondence)
- Series I. Class Notes and Exams, 1932 - 1940; 37892
  - Class notes 1932-34, 1927-1967; 46486 (Folder 1)
  - Arch 530 class notes of Walter Johnson, 1932-1933; 46487 (Folder 2)
  - Arch 430b final exams, 1933; 46488 (Folder 3)
  - Arch 430b final exams, 1934; 46489 (Folder 4)
  - Arch 430 final exam papers for various students, 1934; 46490 (Folder 5)
  - Arch 100/Arch 530 Class Notes, 1934-35, 1934-1935; 46491 (Folder 6)
  - Arch 330 Exam Questions/Solutions, 1936 – 1942; 46492 (Folder 7)
  - Arch 530 Exam Questions/solutions, 1937 - 1940; 46493 (Folder 8)
  - Arch 330, 530 Class notes, 46494 (Folder 9)
- Series II. Programs and Projects, 1929 - 1933; 46478
  - Proposed building program – Galveston Public Schools, c. 1929, 46479 (Folder 10)
  - Construction costs for projects, 1932 – 1933; 46480 (Folder 11)
  - Construction costs publications, 1932 – 1933; 46481 (Folder 12)
- Series III. Correspondence, 46482
  - Correspondence, 1922; 46483 (Folder 13)
  - Rice Architecture alumni correspondence 1956, 46484 (Folder 14)
- Series IV. Plans, Estimates, 46485
  - Plans loaned out (list), 1958 – 1967; 46500 (Folder 15)
  - Model plans, n.d, 46501 (Folder 16)
  - Architecture Department proposed practice content 1961, 46502 (Folder 17)
  - Cost data estimates, 1927 – 1933; 46503 (Folder 18)
- Series V. Publications, Plans, Course Catalogs, 46495
  - Architecture Society publications, 46496 (Folder 19)
  - Royal Institute of British Architects publications, 46497 (Folder 20)
  - House plans, finishing schedules, n.d., 46498 (Folder 21)
  - Harvard University Graduate School of Architectures course catalog, 1935 - 1936; 46499 (Folder 22)